Guide to the Robert Ward Papers, 1910-2012 and undated RL.01344
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Instrumental Works, 1942-2010 and undated; 4
  - Fiesta Processional, 1967-1977 and undated; 42
    - ECS Publishing Wind Ensemble sampler, 1996 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0048)
    - TAC Band, Music Educators National Conference, Ocean City, Maryland, 1 March 1991 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0136)
    - Keystone Winds, conducted by Jack Stamp, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0218)
    - The Keystone Wind Ensemble, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0068)
    - Night Fantasy: Music for Winds, by the Keystone Wind Ensemble, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0086)
    - Music sketches and full score master sheets, undated (Box 72)
    - Condensed score for concert band, 1969 (Box 65)
  - Five x Five: Four Variations on a Five-Part Theme, 1989-1900 and undated; 43
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
    - Conducted by Pavel Prantl, takes 73-103, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0003)
    - Edited production master, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0020)
    - Bakersfield Symphony, 22 April 1990 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0101)
    - Bakersfield Symphony, digital editing by John M Proffitt, Undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0102)
    - Prague Chamber Orchestra, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0103)
    - Premiere, Dekalb Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Robert Ward, 23 May 1989 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0183)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0184)
    - Augusta Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Harry Jacobs, 3 November 1990 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0185)
    - Augusta Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Harry Jacobs, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0186)
    - Dekalb Symphony Orchestra, High Bias Dolby B, 23 May 1989 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0205)
    - World premiere, 1999 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0088)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 65)
    - Orchestral scores, 1989; 2 folders (Box 65)
  - Four Abstractions for Band, 1981-1994 and undated; 44
    - Program, letter, 1985-1994 (Box 10)
    - Unknown performers, 7 August 1775 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0002)
    - ECS Publishing Wind Ensemble sampler, 1996 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0048)
    - Colorado State University Wind Ensemble, 18 November 1985 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0162)
    - MTSU Composition competition, 21 April 1994 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0204)
    - Keystone Winds, conducted by Jack Stamp, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0218)
    - American Masters Concert II: The Music of Robert Ward, 10 March 2002 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0040)
    - The Keystone Wind Ensemble, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0068)
    - Night Fantasy: Music for Winds, by the Keystone Wind Ensemble, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0086)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Full scores and incomplete parts with some markings, 1981; 3 folders (Box 66)
      Missing mvt. I harp/piano part
    - Conductor's score with markings, undated (Box 73)
  - Hymn and Celebration, 1962-1969 and undated; 45
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, 1962-1969 (Box 10)
    - University of Tennessee Orchestra and Wind Ensemble, 16 May 1981 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0206)
    - Hymn and Celebration (for Dubs), undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0207)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0208)
    - Premiere, Phoenix Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Guy Taylor, 27 March 1962 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0017)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Orchestral score, 1969 (Box 66)
    - Orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 73)
    - Conductor's score with revisions, undated (Box 73)
  - Invocation and Toccata, 1975-1996 and undated; 46
    Original title: Music for a Celebration
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, 1983-1996 (Box 10)
    - Contemporary Youth Orchestra, 23 March 2003 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0037)
    - The Polish National Radio Orchestra, conducted by William Strickland, 2000 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0004)
    - Polish Radio Orchestra, 1989 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0066)
    - Polish Radio Orchestra, conducted by Bodhan Wodiczko and Zdzislav Szostak, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0018)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Orchestral score, 1975 (Box 66)
    - Conductor's score with revisions, undated (Box 74)
  - Jonathan and the Gingery Snare, 1949-2008 and undated; 47
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1949-1999 (Box 10)
    - Program sketches, visual sketches, performance photographs, slides, 2008 and undated (Box 10)
    - North Carolina Symphony, conducted by Jackson Parkhurst, 1990 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0150)
    - Young People's Concert, North Carolina Public Television, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0151)
    - Raleigh Dance Theatre, 1 November 2008 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0060)
    - Raleigh Dance Theatre, 1 November 2008 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0061)
    - Raleigh Dance Theatre, 1 November 2008 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0062)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0074)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Full score, master copy, undated (Box 66)
    - Full score, manuscript and concert band copies, undated (Box 66)
    - Full score master sheets, undated (Box 74)
    - Piano reductions with markings, 1951 (Box 66)
    - Conductor's score, undated (Box 74)
  - Jubilation, An Overture, 1946-2007 and undated; 48
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1946-2007; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Gerhardt Zimmerman, 1988 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0025)
    - Robert Ward Celebration, final edit, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0032)
    - North Carolina Symphony, version two, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0044)
    - North Carolina Symphony, 8 October 1987 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0067)
    - National Repertory Orchestra, conducted by Carl Topilow, 30 June 2001 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0034)
    - American Masters Concert II: The Music of Robert Ward, 10 March 2002 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0040)
    - Seattle Youth Symphony, 26 November 1984 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0003)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0002)
    - The Vienna Symphony Orchestra, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0013)
    - North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, 1988 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0017)
    - Test pressing, North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, 1988 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0021)
    - University of Southern California Trojan Symohonic Band, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0026)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0044)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0043)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Orchestral score, 1949 (Box 66)
    - Orchestral miniature score, 1949 (Box 66)
    - Concert band full score and complete parts with some markings, 1958; 2 folders (Box 66)
    - Orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 74)
    - Conductor's score with revisions, undated (Box 74)
  - Lamentation and Scherzo, 1947-1987 and undated; 49
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, 1947-1987 (Box 10)
    - Michael Ching on piano, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0169)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0176)
    - Carolyn Billings on piano, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0201)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0044)
    - Echoes in America: Chamber Music of Robert Ward, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0069)
    - Unknown performers, 1990 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0087)
    - Music sketches and master sheets, undated (Box 74)
    - Score for Lamentation, 1948 (Box 66)
    - Full score, 1984 (Box 66)
  - Music for Celebration, 1963 and undated; 50
    Retitled Invocation and Toccata by composer; Alternate title: Music for a Great Occasion
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Premiere, Erie Philharmonic, conducted by James Sample, 19 November 1963 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0008)
    - Orchestral score with revisions, undated; 11" x 17" (Box 74)
  - Movement for String Quartet, undated; 51
    - Full score with markings, master sheets, undated (Box 74)
  - Night Fantasy, 1962-1972 and undated; 52
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, press release, 1963-1972 (Box 10)
    - MTSU Composition competition, 21 April 1994 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0204)
    - University of Tennessee Orchestra and Wind Ensemble, 16 May 1981 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0206)
    - Keystone Winds, conducted by Jack Stamp, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0218)
    - The Keystone Wind Ensemble, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0068)
    - Night Fantasy: Music for Winds, by the Keystone Wind Ensemble, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0086)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0044)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0043)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Concert band bull score, 1962 (Box 66)
    - Condensed score master sheets, ful score with revisions, undated (Box 75)
  - Night Music, 1949-1951 and undated; 53
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1949-1951 (Box 10)
    - Orchestral score with revisions, undated (Box 75)
  - Night Under the Big Sky, 1997-1998 and undated; 54
    - Program, 1997 (Box 10)
    - SAI Quintet, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0037)
    - The Chamber Music Society of Wilmington, 27 April 2003 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0073)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Full score and complete parts, 1998 (Box 66)
  - Prairie Overture, 1957-2002 and undated; 55
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1967-2002 (Box 10)
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1967-2002 (Box 11)
    - Greenville Symphony, 27 February 1988 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0038)
    - Tactical Air Command Band, Fayetteville, North Carolina, 24 April 1990 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0039)
    - The Western Piedmont Orchestra, conducted by John Gordon, 11 October 1997 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0040)
    - University of Tennessee Orchestra and Wind Ensemble, 16 May 1981 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0206)
    - Keystone Winds, conducted by Jack Stamp, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0218)
    - The Polish National Radio Orchestra, conducted by William Strickland, 2000 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0004)
    - Contemporary Youth Orchestra, 23 March 2003 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0037)
    - Polish Radio Orchestra, 1989 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0066)
    - America's Band in Blue, Travis Air Force Base, California, March 1992 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0067)
    - The Keystone Wind Ensemble, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0068)
    - Night Fantasy: Music for Winds, by the Keystone Wind Ensemble, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0086)
    - Polish Radio Orchestra, conducted by Bodhan Wodiczko and Zdzislav Szostak, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0018)
    - Transylvania Concert Band, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0004)
    - Final concert and rehearsal, Kin Haven Orchestra, conducted by Aorian Gnam, 13 August 1963 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0011)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 76)
    - Orchestral score and complete parts, 1964; 2 folders (Box 66)
    - Concert band full score, 1960 (Box 66)
    - Master sheets for concert band version, undated (Box 76)
    - Conductor's score for concert band version, 1957 (Box 76)
  - Processional March, undated; 56
    - Music sketches, original manuscript, orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 75)
  - The Promised Land, 1977 and undated; 57
    - Program notes, undated (Box 11)
    - "On Jordan's Stormy Banks," Unknown performers, undated (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0004)
      Optional chorale
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 75)
    - Full score, 1977 (Box 66)
    - Conductor's score, undated (Box 75)
  - Quintet for Oboe and String Quartet, 2006-2008 and undated; 58
    - Programs, 2006-2008 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, 2008 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0014)
    - Ciompi Quartet and Joseph Robinson, oboe, 14 January 2008 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0075)
    - Ciompi Quartet, 24 February 2007 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0077)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Full score and complete parts with some markings, 2006; 2 folders (Box 66)
    - Original unrevised score and parts, 2006 (Box 66)
    - Original manuscript and photocopy, undated (Box 75)
  - Quintet for Piano and Strings, 1991; 59
    - Programs, 1991 (Box 11)
  - Raleigh Divertimento, 1986-2007 and undated; 60
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1986-2007 (Box 11)
    - University of Wisconsin students and faculty, September 1989 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0064)
    - Aspen Wind Quintet, 19 January 1986 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0096)
    - Aspen Wind Quintet premiere, recorded by WUNC, Chapel Hill, NC, 19 January 1986 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0097)
    - Aspen Wind Quintet, 1991 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0063)
    - Brevard Symphony Orchestra, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0169)
    - Dorian Wind Quintet, 1999 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0002)
    - Unknown performers, 2008 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0014)
    - Czech Nonet, 22 May 2007 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0025)
    - Czech Nonet, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0027)
    - Czech Nonet, listening copy, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0032)
    - Echoes in America: Chamber Music of Robert Ward, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0069)
    - The Chamber Music Society of Wilmington, 27 April 2003 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0073)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Full score and complete parts, 1986 (Box 66)
  - Rhapsody for Bath County, 1991 and undated; 61
    - Newspaper clipping, program, 1991 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, 2008 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0014)
    - Unknown performers, 12:14, 1 September 1991 (Box 30)
      7.5
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 66)
    - Full score and complete parts, 1991; 2 folders (Box 66)
  - The Rolling Seventh, undated; 62
    - Duke University Wind Symphony, conducted by J. Randal Guptill, 2 March 2006 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0033)
    - Orchestral score and manuscript copy, undated; 11" x 14" (Box 75)
  - The Scarlet Letter, 1989-1993 and undated; 63
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, choreography synopsis, 1992-1993 (Box 11)
    - Winston-Salem Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, 11 March 1990 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0111)
    - Suite from the Ballet, Winston-Salem Piedmont Triad Orchestra, conducted by Peter Perret, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0112)
    - Winston-Salem Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, 8 October 1991 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0113)
      Includes note: "best performance by far"
    - Complete ballet, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0114)
    - Winston-Salem Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0115)
    - Excerpts, Winston-Salem Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0116)
    - Winston-Salem Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0118)
    - Winston-Salem Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0120)
    - Winston-Salem Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, 6 October 1991 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0121)
    - Winston-Salem Piedmont Triad Orchestra, conducted by Peter Perret, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0117)
    - Dubbed from master CD, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0119)
    - Suite from The Scarlet Letter, Winston-Salem Triad Piedmont Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, 1994 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0070)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0074)
    - Live afternoon and evening performances, 15 May 1993, 16 May 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0006)
    - Live evening performances, 13 May 1993, 14 May 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0009)
    - Assorted sketches, 1989 (Box 67)
      Includes music sketches, choreography, and libretto drafts
    - Orchestral scores with markings, 1989-1991 and undated; 4 folders (Box 67)
      Includes Robert Ward's copy with markings and separate score for Part V, "Wild Night of Remorse"
    - Orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 67)
    - Original manuscripts and copies, undated (Box 85)
  - Serenade for Mallarmé, 1991-1997 and undated; 64
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1991-1997 (Box 11)
    - Safety copy, 14 May 1992 (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0029)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0032)
    - Mallarmé Chamber Players, 15 October 1991 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0086)
    - North Carolina Composers' Symposium, Salem College, 10 April 1992 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0090)
    - Davidsbund Chamber Players, 8 March 1992 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0091)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0099)
    - Second movement, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0116)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0168)
    - Unknown performers, 1996 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0016)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0074)
    - Music sketches and original manuscript, undated (Box 67)
    - Full score and incomplete parts, 1991 (Box 67)
      Missing flute part
  - Serenade for Strings, undated; 65
    - Orchestral score with revisions, undated (Box 75)
  - Slow Music for Orchestra, undated; 66
    - Original manuscript, conductor's score, orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 75)
  - First Sonata for Violin and Piano, 1950-1996 and undated; 67
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1950-1980 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0032)
    - Music for Our Times, WCPE, 2 October 1987 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0050)
    - Vartan Manoogian and Anne Epperson, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0093)
    - Robert Ward works for violin and piano, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0094)
      Vartan Manoogian and Anne Epperson, Nicholas Kitchen and Curt Cacioppo, S Shipps and E. Larsen
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0095)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0168)
    - Unknown performers, 1996 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0016)
    - Robert Ward Chamber Music, 1979 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0009)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 32, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0056)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 75)
    - Full score and violin part with master sheets, 1996; 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Full score with revisions, undated; 11" x 14" (Box 75)
  - Second Sonata for Violin and Piano, 1991-1995 and undated; 68
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1991-1995 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, 11 January 1992 (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0027)
      Includes timing breakdowns on liner notes
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0032)
    - Rehearsal with Robert Ward, 8 January 1991 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0081)
    - Nicholas Kitchen and Curt Cacioppo working with Robert Ward, 8 January 1991 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0085)
    - Vartan Manoogian and John Ruggero, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0087)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0088)
    - Nicholas Kitchen and Curt Cacioppo, 10 January 1991 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0089)
    - Nicholas Kitchen, edited master, 11 January 1992 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0092)
    - Robert Ward works for violin and piano, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0094)
      Nicholas Kitchen and Curt Cacioppo
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0168)
    - Unknown performers, 1996 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0016)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0007)
    - Music sketches and revisions, undated (Box 67)
    - Full score and violin part, 1992 (Box 67)
  - Sonic Structure, 1980-1988 and undated; 69
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, letter, 1980-1988 (Box 11)
    - North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Gerhardt Zimmerman, 1988 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0025)
    - Robert Ward Celebration, final edit, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0032)
    - North Carolina Symphony, version two, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0044)
    - Nashville Symphony, 26 September 1980 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0077)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0078)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0079)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0127)
    - North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, 1988 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0017)
    - Test pressing, North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, 1988 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0021)
    - Nashville Symphony, conducted by Mike Charry, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0027)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 67)
    - Orchestral scores, 1988 and undated (Box 67)
    - Revised orchestral score, undated (Box 67)
    - Orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 77)
  - First String Quartet, 1966-1992 and undated; 70
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1966-1986 (Box 10)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0099)
    - Ciompi Quartet, Concert at the National Gallery, Washington D.C., 18 May 1986 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0100)
    - Ciompi Quartet, 15 December 1992 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0131)
    - Ciompi Quartet, 1992 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0009)
    - Robert Ward Chamber Music, 1979 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0009)
    - Sch. 17th Annual Forum, Milwaukee Symphony, mono, 3 October 1966 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0033)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 32, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0057)
    - Music sketches, original manuscript, full score, undated (Box 74)
    - Full score and complete parts with some markings, 1966 (Box 65)
  - First Symphonic Set, The New South, undated; 71
    Based on music from Claudia Legare; Sketches for "Industrialize and Rise," and general revisions
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 67)
    - Orchestral score with markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 67)
  - First Symphonic Set from Lady Kate, 1988; 72
    - Program, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Second Symphonic Set from Lady Kate, 2004; 73
    - Program, 2004 (Box 11)
  - Second Symphonic Set from Lady from Colorado, 1989; 74
    - Program, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Orchestral score and program notes, 1989 (Box 67)
  - Symphony No. 1, 1942-1958 and undated; 75
    Alternate title: First Symphony
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1947-1958 (Box 11)
    - Conducted by Pavel Prantl, takes 1-43, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0001)
    - Edited production master, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0020)
    - Music for Our Times, WCPE, 1 October 1987 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0050)
    - Bakersfield Symphony, 22 April 1990 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0101)